<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<collection>
    <recipe>
        <title>Egg Benedict</title>
        <preptime>30 min</preptime>
        <img>egg_benedict.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>2 fresh English muffins,4 eggs,4 rashers of back bacon,2 egg yolks,1 tbsp of lemon juice,125 g of butter,salt and pepper</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Start with the bacon. Heat a large skillet on medium low heat,*Add the strips of bacon or the slices of Canadian bacon,*While the bacon is cooking bring a large saucepan two-thirds-filled with water to a boil then add the vinegar,*Poach the eggs as soon as all the eggs are in the poaching water begin toasting your English muffins.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Mushroom Risotto</title>
        <preptime>30 min</preptime>
        <img>mushroom_risotto.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>1 tbsp dried porcini mushrooms, 2 tbsp olive oil, 1 onion chopped, 2 garlic cloves, 350g/12oz arborio rice", 1.2 litres/2 pints hot vegetable stock, salt and pepper, 25g/1oz butter</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Heat the chicken broth in a medium saucepan and keep warm over low heat,*Heat 1 tablespoon of oil in a large skillet over medium heat,*Add 1/2 onion and 1 clove garlic cook stirring until translucent about 5 minutes,*Coat a saucepan with remaining 2 tablespoons of oil Saute the remaining 1/2 onion and garlic clove,*Add the rice and stir quickly until it is well-coated and opaque 1 minute,*This step cooks the starchy coating and prevents the grains from sticking,*Stir in wine and cook until it is nearly all evaporated.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Full Breakfast</title>
        <preptime>20 min</preptime>
        <img>full_breakfast.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>2 sausages, 100 grams of mushrooms, 2 rashers of bacon, 2 eggs, 150 grams of baked beans, Vegetable oil</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Heat the flat grill plate over a low heat, on top of 2 rings/flames if it fits and brush sparingly with light olive oil,*Cook the sausages first add the sausages to the hot grill plate/the coolest part if there is one and allow to cook slowly for about 15-20 minutes turning occasionally until golden,*Once all the ingredients are cooked serve on warm plates and enjoy straight away with a good squeeze of tomato ketchup or brown sauce.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Hamburger</title>
        <preptime>30 min</preptime>
        <img>hamburger.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>400g of ground beef, 1/4 onion (minced), 1 tbsp butter, hamburger bun, 1 teaspoon dry mustard, Salt and pepper</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Divide the meat into four 6 ounce (170 gram) pucks about 1.25 inches thick by 3 inches wide,*Lightly oil a cast iron skillet or griddle by adding a little vegetable oil and spreading it around with a paper towel soaking up any excess oil,*Heat over medium high heat toast your bun and slather a generous amount of sauce onto the bottom bun,*Top with onions and then the burger patty then the tomatoes and finally the lettuce and top bun,*I use this order because the weight of the burger keeps the onion rings in place while the heat slightly cooks them</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Ham and Egg Sandwich</title>
        <preptime>10 min</preptime>
        <img>ham_and_egg_sandwich.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>1 unsliced loaf (1 pound) French bread, 4 tablespoons butter, 2 tablespoons mayonnaise, 8 thin slices deli ham, 1 large tomato, sliced, 1 small onion, 8 eggs, 8 slices cheddar cheese</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Preheat oven to 375 cut bread in half lengthwise carefully hollow out top and bottom leaving 1/2-in,*A large skillet melt remaining butter add eggs,*Cook over medium heat stirring occasionally until edges are almost set,*Spoon into bottom bread shell top with cheese,*Cover with bread top.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Creme Brelee</title>
        <preptime>1 hour</preptime>
        <img>creme_brelee.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>1 quart heavy cream,1 vanilla bean, split and scraped, 1 cup vanilla sugar, 6 large egg yolks, 2 quarts hot water,</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Place the cream vanilla bean and its pulp into a medium saucepan set over medium-high heat and bring to a boil,*Remove from the heat cover and allow to sit for 15 minutes,*Remove the vanilla bean and reserve for another use,*In a medium bowl whisk together 1/2 cup sugar and the egg yolks until well blended and it just starts to lighten in color,*Add the cream a little at a time stirring continually,*Pour the liquid into 6 (7 to 8-ounce) ramekins.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>White Chocolate Donut</title>
        <preptime>45 min</preptime>
        <img>white_chocolate_donut.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>3 1/4 cups flour,2 teaspoons baking powder, 1/4 teaspoon salt, 2 beaten eggs, 2/3 cup sugar, 2 ounces melted white chocolate, 1/2 cup milk</ingredients>
        <preparation>*In a mixing bowl whisk the eggs and sugar together,*Add the melted chocolate and butter Stir in the milk and vanilla,*Slowly add the sifted flour into the egg mixture incorporate into a soft dough,*Place the doughnuts on a platter.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Vegetable Curry</title>
        <preptime>30 min</preptime>
        <img>vegetable_curry.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>1 tablespoon olive oil, 1 onion, chopped, 2 cloves garlic, 2 1/2 tablespoons curry powder, 2 quarts hot water</ingredients>
        <preparation>*In a large saucepan over medium-high heat oil and saute onion and garlic until golden,*Stir in curry powder and tomato paste cook 2 to 3 minutes,*Stir in tomatoes vegetable bouillon cube mixed vegetables water salt and pepper to taste,*Cook approximately 30 minutes until vegetables are well done (not crunchy),*Sprinkle with fresh cilantro prior to serving.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Instant Noodle with Egg</title>
        <preptime>8 min</preptime>
        <img>instant_noodle_with_egg.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>1 pack of Instant Noodle, 2 eggs</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Bring 2 1/2 cups of water to a boil in a small saucepan,*Add the noodles and cook for 2 minutes,*Add the flavor packet stir and continue to cook for another 30 seconds.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Noodle with BBQ Pork</title>
        <preptime>20 min</preptime>
        <img>noodle_with_bbq_pork.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>1 pack of Instant Noodle, BBQ pork, Salt and Pepper</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Put the noodles in the bowl add a tablespoon of fried garlic and mix the noodles well so they don't stick together,*Add fish sauce sugar vinegar and ground chili pepper,*Sprinkle sliced green onion and cilantro and pickled cabbage*Slice barbeque pork 1/8 inch thick and add it to the noodles,*Top with fried garlic and a dash of ground white pepper.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Japanese Noodle with Pork</title>
        <preptime>20 min</preptime>
        <img>japanese_noodle_with_pork.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>1 pack of Japanese Noodle, 2 green onions, 2 garlic cloves, minced, 4 boneless pork loin chops</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Add 2 tablespoons oil,*Add the carrots and onions and saute until they begin to caramelize,*Next add the ginger  garlic and habanero,*Saute until the vegetables become aromatic about 1 minute,*Add the remaining 2 tablespoons oil and the mushrooms and cabbage,*Stir in the tamari sauce chicken stock and pork,*Reduce the heat to low cover and let simmer about 20 minutes.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Ham and Cheese Panini</title>
        <preptime>10 min</preptime>
        <img>ham_and_cheese_panini.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>2 tablespoons unsalted butter, 4 cups thinly sliced shallots, 2 teaspoons fresh thyme, 1/4 cup grainy Dijon mustard, 8 slices rustic white bread, 8 slices Gruyere cheese, 8 ounces sliced cooked ham</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Reheat a stovetop panini grill a heavy saute pan,*Match up the bread slices creating 4 even pairs and then lightly butter the outside of each slice,*For each sandwich place 1 bread slice buttered side down on a work surface and layer with 2 cheese slices then 2 tomato slices,*Season with salt and pepper then add another 2 cheese slices 1 or 2 ham slices and then 2 more cheese slices.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    
    <recipe>
        <title>Thai Shrimp Caket</title>
        <preptime>1.5 hours</preptime>
        <img>thai_shrimp_cake.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>8 oz (250g) peeled and deveined raw shrimp, 2 tablespoons red curry paste, 1 large egg, 2 teaspoon fish sauce, 1 tablespoon sugar, 2 tablespoons coconut milk, 2 tablespoons roughly chopped Thai basil leaves</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Combine 1/3 cup panko 2 tablespoons coconut and next 8 ingredients in a large bowl,*Add shrimp stir just until combined shape mixture into 4 equal balls,*Combine remaining panko and coconut in a shallow dish,*Coat balls in panko mixture press to form 4 (4-inch) patties,*Heat a large nonstick skillet over medium-high heat,*Add oil swirl to coat Add patties cook 4 minutes on each side or until desired degree of doneness,*Serve with lime.</preparation>
    </recipe>
    
    <recipe>
        <title>White Chocolate Mocha</title>
        <preptime>5 min</preptime>
        <img>starbucks_coffee.jpg</img>
        <ingredients>2/3 cup whole milk, 6 tablespoons white chocolate chips, coffee, whipped cream</ingredients>
        <preparation>*Pour milk into a steaming pitcher and heat to 145 degrees F to 165 degrees F (65 to 70 degrees C) using the steaming wand,*Measure the white chocolate syrup into a large coffee mug,*Brew espresso then add to mug,*Pour the steamed milk into the mug using a spoon to hold back the foam,*Top with whipped cream and serve.</preparation>
    </recipe>  
</collection>